Summary

Network Engineer/Network Support, where more than 6 years of progressive technical experience will add value. MCP and CCNA certifications will add value. Able to drive and deliver results and thrive in a fast-paced, 24/7 environment. Has strong analytical, decision-making, organizational, communication, and customer-service skills. English proficient and has the ability to multitask.

Experience

Tier 2 Network Support Engineer: Concentrix Philippines – Windstream (Jan 2015 – Present)

- Tier II Repair Engineer for troubleshooting, configuration, and maintenance of VOIP phone system, Internet Dedicated Access, and MPLS product for Broadview customers.
- Tier II Repair Engineer for troubleshooting network issues (Circuit down, slow speed, etc.)
- Tier II Repair Engineer for troubleshooting VOIP issues such as One Way Audio, Static, dropped calls, any call quality issues etc.
- Troubleshoot, test, and repair T1 and Ethernet circuits.
- Coordinates with other Telcos and vendors to troubleshoot and report issues.

Network Implementation Engineer: Accenture - Verizon Business Project (May 2012- Dec 2014)

- Tier II Implementation Engineer for Verizon Business MPLS Customers
- Tier II Implementation Engineer for Verizon Business Internet Customers
- Ensures that Layer3 is properly working in both the CE and PE routers
- Responsible for doing tests on the circuit to ensure that the circuit is clean and error free.
- Liaises with other Telco Company for Network to Network Interface troubleshooting during WAN turn-up.
- Coordinates with the Project Manager, Field Engineer, Customer, Layer 1 Group and other Telecom partners.
- Assists Field Engineer in installing and connecting CPE devices such as routers, switches, Layer 1&2 device and Out of Band (OOB) modems
- Ensures configurations meet customer expectations as well as industry and product standards.
- Experienced in the use of network routing protocols (EIGRP, OSPF and BGP) and Layer 2 technologies (MLPPP, PPP, VLAN).
- Extensive knowledge of WAN connections such as HDLC, PPP (Leased line) and Framerelay (Packet switched).
- Extensive hands-on configuration in T1/DS1, T3/DS3, OC, Ethernet circuits.
- Assists Field Engineer in installing and connecting CPE devices such as routers, switches, Digiport Servers, Visual Fluke and Out of Band (OOB) modems.
- Responsible for the documentation of every network activities performed.

Experience Continued

Internet Café and Freelance PC Troubleshooting – (Mar 2010 – Feb 2012)

• Worked on my own Internet Café business and did freelance PC troubleshooting and repair.

Specialist Network Engineer: Verizon Services Communications Phil. Managed Service Delivery Installations Group – (June 2008 – Feb 2010)

- Implementation of Verizon Business Customers MPLS enterprise network projects.
- Perform router/switch network hardware & software upgrades;
- Implement networks using BGP, OSPF, EIGRP, HSRP, and other protocols.
- Customer Edge Router configuration, testing, upgrade, and troubleshooting: MPLS cicuits-T1, Frac-T1, Multilink PPP, DS3, OC3.
- Installation and configuration of Fluke Networks Visual Probe devices.
- Installation and configuration of Adtran and Juniper Routers
- Update and document network diagrams.
- Modem/CSU DSU configuration and Installation.

Network Core Engineer: INFONXX Phil. Global Network Operations - (Sept 2007 – Mar 2008)

- Troubleshoot, manage, and maintain, INFONXX LAN and WAN network infrastructure.
- Configuration of Cisco Routers and Switches. Monitoring the health, performance, and utilization of all networking devices and servers thru the use of network monitoring tools like HP Openview, MRTG, Nagios, Solarwinds, and Whats Up Gold.
- Incident and fault handling of circuit bounces and any network errors. Assisting WAN provider to troubleshoot the connectivity problem of WAN routers.
- Coordinates and interfaces with US/UK Network engineers, vendors, carriers, Telco's, customers, and ISP's to drive the issue to resolution.
- Prepare and update technical documentation, network (physical and logical) diagram, reports and Standard Operation Procedures & inventory listing.
- Assist other teams in problem resolution and troubleshooting.
- Performing the network related incident and change management (hardware and software upgrades).

Technical Customer Care Representative: Convergys Services Philippines Co., Q.C. Broadband DSL account. (Sept 2005 – April 2006)

- Troubleshooting internet connectivity issues, DSL configuration and diagnostics, authentication and web page troubleshooting, dial-up configuration and troubleshooting, latency troubleshooting, virus removal, and installation assistance.
- Has gained a good reputation in customer satisfaction for the whole 8 month period.
- Top 3 agent for January 2006

EDUCATION

HS: Quezon City Science H.S.

College: BS Physical Therapy University of the Philippines — Undergraduate **Advance Diploma in Information Technology: Informatics Computer Institute** — Undergraduate

TRAINING

- PC Troubleshooting and Networking Informatics Computer Institute
- ISA Server 2006 Technical Overview Microsoft Philippines
- Group Policy in Windows Vista Microsoft Philippines
- Cisco Certified Network Associate Mapua Cisco Networking Academy
- Managing and Maintaining a Microsoft Windows Server 2003 Environment DB Wizards (Microsoft Gold Partner for Learning Solutions)
- Implementing, Managing, and Maintaining a Microsoft Windows Server 2003 Network Infrastructure - DB Wizards
- **CCNP BSCI Training** Rivan Systems
- **CCNP BCMSN Training** Rivan Systems
- **CCNP ISCW Training** Rivan Systems
- **CCNP ISCW ONT** Rivan Systems

CERTIFICATIONS

- 70-270 Installing, Configuring, and Administering Microsoft Windows XP Professional
- 70-290 Managing and Maintaining a Windows Server 2003 Environment
- 640-801 Cisco Certified Network Associate (Expired last 2016)

Developer Portfolio

https://shanearleighagres.github.io/devportfolio/